SARON MELES

Contact

Address:

Addis Ababa, Bole Wereda 6,

Phone:

- +251929040556
- +251920184946

Email:

saronmeles4@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/saron-meles/

Languages

English

Read, write and speak well

Amharic

Read, write and speak well

Chinese

Basic Communication (HSK-level-3)

Skills

Programming

• MySQL, Express, React, Node.js(MERN-Stack), JavaScript, Bootstrap,HTML5, CSS3, MUI.

Software

AWS, Adobe XD,
WIX, VS Code, GIT,
Oracle NetSuite,
Microsoft Office
Platforms, Windows
and Linux OS.

Personal skills

- Team work
- Written and verbal communication
- Time management

Summary

A Computer Engineer with 2 years of experience working under Software Project Implementation Department, able to build fully responsive websites from the ground up – requirement analysis, planning, design, development, testing and delivery and maintenance. I'm Recognized for collaborative abilities when working in team settings and motivated to provide clients with user-friendly solutions following the agile approach. And I am always eager to learn new technologies and stay up to date with the latest technology trends.

Experience

IT Technician

West International Holdings Africa Co. Ltd (Software Project Implementation Department)

1-07-2021 - Present

- Website Designing, developing and maintenance. (Successfully built more than 12 websites)
- Develop websites for different subsidiary companies in African countries. (Nigeria, Angola, Congo, Mozambique, Rwanda, Ethiopia...)
- Operation and management of Oracle NetSuite ERP system, OA system, TMS, MES.

Intern Electrical and Computer Engineer

Transsion Manufacturing Plc (Goro ICT Park) 09-2019 - 02-2020

- Collaborated and worked with Mobile phone Assembly and packaging process control department.
- Carried out a project "Autonomous Accessory Pick and Place Robotic Arm" to replace the manual work. (Simulation level)

Education

BSc. in **Electrical and Computer Engineering**With **Computer Engineering** Major. (09/2016 - 02/2021).

Jimma University, Jimma Institute of Technology (JIT).

CGPA - 3.23

Relevant Projects

- "Aiding visually impaired using smart stick" using Arduino micro controller and C programming.
- "Autonomous seed sowing robotic vehicle" using Proteus and MikroC for PIC.
- "Safe Crowd Size and Distance Monitoring System for COVID-19 protection" for final project.

- Work under pressure and meet deadlines.
- Adaptable to new situation.
- Creativity and problemsolving.

Certification

- Computer Networking and Maintenance.
- Project Management Professionals (PMP Basics)
- Excellent Personnel 2021 honorary certificate.